Andy Piffer

Game Designer & Product Manager

+55 11 99254-0970 4piffer@gmail.com https://apiffer.com

Hi! I'm Andy, and I'm currently looking to join a studio as a **Game Designer**. Since 2011, I've collaborated to create more than 50 fun casual mobile games that made millions of people smile worldwide. In addition, as a former Product Manager, I've led teams of up to 20 creative minds – from discovery to live-ops phases – into building popular and profitable games through goal oriented, iterative, collaborative, and data-informed processes.

Some successful contributions includes: <u>leading Logic Pic</u>, an "abandoned" 3 years old puzzle, into a marketable and profitable game by experimenting systems, progression, and monetization strategies; and <u>designing My Boo</u>, a tamagotchi-style game downloaded by more than 40 million players and surpassed a million dollar revenue mark. You may check other games in my <u>portfolio</u>.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Game Designer (New Games), Indie & Contract, Nov 2021 – Present (2 years)

Discovery, research and development of casual games prototypes for product-market fit evaluation and KPIs measurement in Mobile and PC markets, either self-funded and financially backed by publishers – such as Voodoo – a top-tier hyper-casual publisher. Activities included: market research and positioning, concepting, game and level design, development in Unity (C#), and creating marketing assets for marketplaces and UA campaigns.

Product Manager, Tapps Games, Jan 2016 – Jul 2019 (3.5 years)

Co-created and led product strategy and game direction with the team and stakeholders using agile and lean methodologies. Managed a roadmap of prioritized opportunities and A/B experiments supported by OKRs, business and partnership goals, market analysis, players' feedback, KPIs and in-game analytics. Furthermore, I've also mentored people from the Product and Game Design team and kickstarted new processes that drastically improve Tapps' research and production phases.

Highlights: Led more than 20 people into discovery, production and soft-launch of "Decor Dream", a hybrid Match-3 with 3D Decoration game (2018-2019), and led multiple squads into making successful live-ops releases for Cow Evolution (2016), Vlogger Go Viral (2016), My Boo (2016-2017), and Logic Pic (2017).

Game Designer, Tapps Games, Jul 2013 – Dec 2015 (2.5 years)

Designed and balanced core-loops, systems, levels, economies, and/or updates for more than 50 casual mobile games of different genres, including successful ones such as My Boo (40+ million downloads). In order to deliver that many releases, I've collaborated with different designers, artists, developers, QAs, sound designers, plus mentored two junior game designers, and created a few dev-tools.

Design Intern, Tapps Games, Aug 2011 – Aug 2012 (1 year)

Pitched and documented new games proposals; designed game levels and user interface.

EDUCATION

Immersive Program in Creative Leadership, Polifonia, Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

Bachelor's Degree in Game Design, Anhembi Morumbi (UAM), 2009 – 2012

- Designed tabletop games and playable prototypes using different technologies
- Published an undergraduate research on Game UX Design (Cognitive Usability)
- Final thesis focusing on Game System Design (Resource Management and Strategy)

RELEVANT EXPERIENCES

"Con Latinidad 2023" - Winner, Oct 2023

One-month game jam organized by Latinx in Gaming in partnership with Google. My relaxing hidden-object game "CADÊ?" was selected as one of the winners based on quality, creativity, and relation to the theme "Your Latinidad" receiving a prize of \$10,000.

2 Years Sabbatical Leave (Travel, Volunteer, Mental Health, Game Jams), Oct 2019 - Sep 2021

- Backpacked over 10 countries across Europe and Asia;
- Volunteered at Southeast Asian NGOs and Startups during pandemic years by teaching English to children/teenagers using custom designed activities/games and by conducting marketing initiatives for fundraising;
- Learned yoga and other mental-health practices at awarded retreats;
- Joined game jams competitions as independent creator, including:
 - "Jam Nation" Winner: One-month game jam hosted by TapNation publisher where 233 development teams from more than 40 countries took part. I won 1st place with my hyper-casual puzzle which had the best KPIs among all games.
 - "Storms the World" Finalist: My game was selected among the Top 10 Games judged based on the game's originality, production quality and market fit.

TECHNICAL & LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Documentation & management: Microsoft Office, Google Suite, JIRA, Confluence, Trello.
- Game development: Excel/Spreadsheets, Unity, Photoshop, Illustrator, Maya.
- Programming: Unity, C#, LUA, HTML, JS, CSS and GIT code-management.
- Data analysis: iTunes Connect, Google Suite (Play Console, Analytics, Firebase), Tableau, Facebook Analytics, Game Analytics, Sensor Tower, App Annie and Game Refinery.
- Languages: Brazilian Portuguese (Native) and English (Fluent).